Mega Seating Plan: Xporter DSA                                              

Open menu

Close menu

1. [Home](https://www.seatingplan.com/)
    
2. [Data Sharing Agreements](https://www.seatingplan.com/dsa)

Select a tab Bronze/Silver (individual teachers) Gold Platinum (via Wonde - UK, Australia, New Zealand) Platinum (via Xporter - UK only) Platinum (via Classlink - US only) Platinum (via Skolon)

Bronze/Silver (individual teachers)

Gold

Platinum (via Wonde - UK, Australia, New Zealand)

Platinum (via Xporter - UK only)

Platinum (via Skolon)

Platinum (via Classlink - US only)

### Data Sharing Agreement

##### Introduction

This document forms a Data Sharing Agreement between Mega Seating Plan Ltd (we, our, us) and your school or other education establishment (you, your) for the transit and protection of your school data. When you share data with Mega Seating Plan, it will be stored on our servers, located within European data boundaries. All personally identifiable data is encrypted. This agreement outlines how Mega Seating Plan protects your data.

##### Transfer and Use of Personal Information

Data is stored in a database located in the European Union. Access to student data (and the ability to decrypt it) is limited to the teacher of that class and other users that the teacher has explicitly agreed to share it with.

##### Support

Support is available via an online support helpdesk. To provide this support, it may be necessary for us to sign in to Mega Seating Plan as one of your teachers, thus allowing us to see student data connected to that teacher.

##### Data Lifecycle

When classes are imported, an expiry date is set by the user (this defaults to one year in the future). On this date, the class and all student data associated with it will be permanently deleted.

When a user account is deleted, all imported data is immediately and permanently deleted.

##### Other documents

For further information, please refer to our [privacy policy](https://www.seatingplan.com/privacy), [data protection statement (including GDPR compliance)](https://www.seatingplan.com/gdpr) and [terms of use](https://www.seatingplan.com/terms).

### Data Sharing Agreement

##### Introduction

This document forms a Data Sharing Agreement between Mega Seating Plan Ltd (we, our, us) and your school or other education establishment (you, your) for the transit and protection of your school data. When you share data with Mega Seating Plan, it will be stored on our servers, located within European data boundaries. All personally identifiable data is encrypted. This agreement outlines how Mega Seating Plan protects your data.

##### Transfer and Use of Personal Information

Data is stored in a database located in the European Union. Access to student data (and the ability to decrypt it) is limited to staff within your school and other users that the teacher has explicitly agreed to share it with.

##### Support

Support is available via an online support helpdesk. To provide this support, it may be necessary for us to sign in to Mega Seating Plan as one of your teachers, thus allowing us to see student data connected to that teacher.

##### Data Lifecycle

Data is updated when it is uploaded via CSV or via an API POST.

When classes are deactivated or deleted from your MIS (i.e. they are present in one upload, but not present in a later upload), they will be archived on Mega Seating Plan for three months; this ensures that teachers can still access seating plans for this class for a period (useful for mid-year class changes). After the three month period, these classes, their students and all related seating plans will be permanently deleted from Mega Seating Plan's servers.

##### Other documents

For further information, please refer to our [privacy policy](https://www.seatingplan.com/privacy), [data protection statement (including GDPR compliance)](https://www.seatingplan.com/gdpr) and [terms of use](https://www.seatingplan.com/terms).

### GroupCall Xporter Data Sharing Agreement

##### Introduction

This document forms a Data Sharing Agreement between Mega Seating Plan Ltd (we, our, us) and your school or other education establishment (you, your) for the transit and protection of your school MIS data. When you share data with Mega Seating Plan, it will be transferred via GroupCall Xporter and stored on our servers, located within European data boundaries. All personally identifiable data is encrypted. This agreement outlines how Mega Seating Plan protects your data.

##### Transfer and Use of Personal Information

When registering for Mega Seating Plan's MIS link (provided by GroupCall Xporter), you will provide consent for us to transfer data within the agreed scopes. This consent is perpetual until either party withdraws it. When you revoke consent, we will cease transferring data from your MIS and delete all of your data that has been stored on our servers. This data deletion will include all student and class data imported from your MIS, but individual teacher user accounts may remain in place to allow their continued use of the Mega Seating Plan platform (with no MIS link). Deletion of data shall take place as soon as is practicable and no later than 72 hours from the withdrawal of consent. Withdrawal of consent does not necessarily terminate any commercial relationship between you and us, and you may continue to take advantage of other benefits of Mega Seating Plan that do not require an MIS link.

Data transferred from your MIS and stored by Mega Seating Plan includes the following:

* Details of teachers at your school, including their name and email address. This is for the purpose of establishing a user account on Mega Seating Plan.
* Details of class groups at your school, including lists of students and associated staff.
* Details of timetables at your school. This is for the purpose of providing planning tools for teachers.
* Details of students at your school, including names, photographs, email address, demographics, SEN status and selected assessment data. This is to allow seating plans to be generated and annotated using this data. All personally-identifiable data is stored encrypted.

Data is stored in a database located in the European Union. Access to student data (and the ability to decrypt it) is limited to the teacher of that class and other users that the teacher has explicitly agreed to share it with. Within Platinum schools, all seating plans are shared with all other users in that school (for the purpose of cover lessons and monitoring).

##### Support

Support is available via an online support helpdesk. To provide this support, it may be necessary for us to sign in to Mega Seating Plan as one of your teachers, thus allowing us to see student data connected to that teacher.

##### Data Lifecycle

We will attempt to synchronise demographic/class data with your MIS (via GroupCall) at least every 24 hours. Due to the nature of GroupCall's caching, some changes may take longer to propagate.

When classes are deactivated or deleted from your MIS, they will be archived on Mega Seating Plan for three months; this ensures that teachers can still access seating plans for this class for a period (useful for mid-year class changes). After the three month period, these classes, their students and all related seating plans will be permanently deleted from Mega Seating Plan's servers.

##### Other documents

For further information, please refer to our [privacy policy](https://www.seatingplan.com/privacy), [data protection statement (including GDPR compliance)](https://www.seatingplan.com/gdpr) and [terms of use](https://www.seatingplan.com/terms).

### Wonde Data Sharing Agreement

##### Introduction

This document forms a Data Sharing Agreement between Mega Seating Plan Ltd (we, our, us) and your school or other education establishment (you, your) for the transit and protection of your school MIS data. When you share data with Mega Seating Plan, it will be transferred via Wonde and stored on our servers, located within European data boundaries. All personally identifiable data is encrypted. This agreement outlines how Mega Seating Plan protects your data.

##### Transfer and Use of Personal Information

When registering for Mega Seating Plan's MIS link (provided by Wonde), you will provide consent for us to transfer data within the agreed scopes. This consent is perpetual until either party withdraws it. When you revoke consent, we will cease transferring data from your MIS and delete all of your data that has been stored on our servers. This data deletion will include all student and class data imported from your MIS, but individual teacher user accounts may remain in place to allow their continued use of the Mega Seating Plan platform (with no MIS link). Deletion of data shall take place as soon as is practicable and no later than 72 hours from the withdrawal of consent. Withdrawal of consent does not necessarily terminate any commercial relationship between you and us, and you may continue to take advantage of other benefits of Mega Seating Plan that do not require an MIS link.

Data transferred from your MIS and stored by Mega Seating Plan includes the following:

* Details of teachers at your school, including their name and email address. This is for the purpose of establishing a user account on Mega Seating Plan.
* Details of class groups at your school, including lists of students and associated staff.
* Details of timetables at your school. This is for the purpose of providing planning tools for teachers.
* Details of students at your school, including names, photographs, email address, demographics, SEN status and selected assessment data. This is to allow seating plans to be generated and annotated using this data. All personally-identifiable data is stored encrypted.

Data is stored in a database located in the European Union. Access to student data (and the ability to decrypt it) is limited to the teacher of that class and other users that the teacher has explicitly agreed to share it with. Within Platinum schools, all seating plans are shared with all other users in that school (for the purpose of cover lessons and monitoring).

##### Support

Support is available via an online support helpdesk. To provide this support, it may be necessary for us to sign in to Mega Seating Plan as one of your teachers, thus allowing us to see student data connected to that teacher.

##### Data Lifecycle

We will attempt to synchronise demographic/class data with your MIS (via Wonde) at least every 24 hours. Due to the nature of Wonde's caching, some changes may take longer to propagate.

When classes are deactivated or deleted from your MIS, they will be archived on Mega Seating Plan for three months; this ensures that teachers can still access seating plans for this class for a period (useful for mid-year class changes). After the three month period, these classes, their students and all related seating plans will be permanently deleted from Mega Seating Plan's servers.

##### Other documents

For further information, please refer to our [privacy policy](https://www.seatingplan.com/privacy), [data protection statement (including GDPR compliance)](https://www.seatingplan.com/gdpr) and [terms of use](https://www.seatingplan.com/terms).

### Wonde Data Sharing Agreement

##### Introduction

This document forms a Data Sharing Agreement between Mega Seating Plan Ltd (we, our, us) and your school or other education establishment (you, your) for the transit and protection of your school MIS data. When you share data with Mega Seating Plan, it will be transferred via Skolon and stored on our servers, located within European data boundaries. All personally identifiable data is encrypted. This agreement outlines how Mega Seating Plan protects your data.

##### Transfer and Use of Personal Information

When registering for Mega Seating Plan's SIS link (provided by Skolon), you will provide consent for us to transfer data within the agreed scopes. This consent is perpetual until either party withdraws it. When you revoke consent, we will cease transferring data from your SIS and delete all of your data that has been stored on our servers. This data deletion will include all student and class data imported from your MIS, but individual teacher user accounts may remain in place to allow their continued use of the Mega Seating Plan platform (with no SIS link). Deletion of data shall take place as soon as is practicable and no later than 72 hours from the withdrawal of consent. Withdrawal of consent does not necessarily terminate any commercial relationship between you and us, and you may continue to take advantage of other benefits of Mega Seating Plan that do not require an SIS link.

Data transferred from your SIS and stored by Mega Seating Plan includes the following:

* Details of teachers at your school, including their name and email address. This is for the purpose of establishing a user account on Mega Seating Plan.
* Details of class groups at your school, including lists of students and associated staff.
* Details of students at your school, including names and selected data. This is to allow seating plans to be generated and annotated using this data. All personally-identifiable data is stored encrypted.

Data is stored in a database located in the European Union. Access to student data (and the ability to decrypt it) is limited to the teacher of that class and other users that the teacher has explicitly agreed to share it with. Within Platinum schools, all seating plans are shared with all other users in that school (for the purpose of cover lessons and monitoring).

##### Support

Support is available via an online support helpdesk. To provide this support, it may be necessary for us to sign in to Mega Seating Plan as one of your teachers, thus allowing us to see student data connected to that teacher.

##### Data Lifecycle

We will attempt to synchronise demographic/class data with your SIS (via Skolon) automatically within a few minutes of a data update on your SIS.

When classes are deactivated or deleted from your SIS, they will be archived on Mega Seating Plan for three months; this ensures that teachers can still access seating plans for this class for a period (useful for mid-year class changes). After the three month period, these classes, their students and all related seating plans will be permanently deleted from Mega Seating Plan's servers.

##### Other documents

For further information, please refer to our [privacy policy](https://www.seatingplan.com/privacy), [data protection statement (including GDPR compliance)](https://www.seatingplan.com/gdpr) and [terms of use](https://www.seatingplan.com/terms).

### Iris Data Sharing Agreement

##### Introduction

This document forms a Data Sharing Agreement between Mega Seating Plan Ltd (we, our, us) and your school or other education establishment (you, your) for the transit and protection of your school MIS data. When you share data with Mega Seating Plan, it will be transferred and stored on our servers, located within European data boundaries. All personally identifiable data is encrypted. This agreement outlines how Mega Seating Plan protects your data.

##### Transfer and Use of Personal Information

When registering for Mega Seating Plan's direct import from iSAMS/Ed:Gen, you will provide consent for us to transfer data within the agreed scopes by sharing your credentials. This consent is perpetual until either party withdraws it. When you revoke consent, we will cease transferring data from your MIS and delete all of your data that has been stored on our servers. This data deletion will include all student and class data imported from your MIS, but individual teacher user accounts may remain in place to allow their continued use of the Mega Seating Plan platform (with no MIS link). Deletion of data shall take place as soon as is practicable and no later than 72 hours from the withdrawal of consent. Withdrawal of consent does not necessarily terminate any commercial relationship between you and us, and you may continue to take advantage of other benefits of Mega Seating Plan that do not require an MIS link.

Data transferred from your MIS and stored by Mega Seating Plan includes the following:

* Details of teachers at your school, including their name, email address and photograph. This is for the purpose of establishing a user account on Mega Seating Plan.
* Details of class groups at your school, including lists of students and associated staff.
* Details of timetables at your school. This is for the purpose of providing planning tools for teachers.
* Details of students at your school, including names, photographs, email address, demographics, SEN status and selected assessment data. This is to allow seating plans to be generated and annotated using this data. All personally-identifiable data is stored encrypted.

Data is stored in a database located in the European Union. Access to student data (and the ability to decrypt it) is limited to the teacher of that class and other users that the teacher has explicitly agreed to share it with. Within Platinum schools, all seating plans are shared with all other users in that school (for the purpose of cover lessons and monitoring).

##### Support

Support is available via an online support helpdesk. To provide this support, it may be necessary for us to sign in to Mega Seating Plan as one of your teachers, thus allowing us to see student data connected to that teacher.

##### Data Lifecycle

We will attempt to synchronise demographic/class data with your MIS at least every 24 hours.

When classes are deactivated or deleted from your MIS, they will be archived on Mega Seating Plan for three months; this ensures that teachers can still access seating plans for this class for a period (useful for mid-year class changes). After the three month period, these classes, their students and all related seating plans will be permanently deleted from Mega Seating Plan's servers.

##### Other documents

For further information, please refer to our [privacy policy](https://www.seatingplan.com/privacy), [data protection statement (including GDPR compliance)](https://www.seatingplan.com/gdpr) and [terms of use](https://www.seatingplan.com/terms).

### ClassLink Data Sharing Agreement

##### Introduction

This document forms a Data Sharing Agreement between Mega Seating Plan Ltd (we, our, us) and your school or other education establishment (you, your) for the transit and protection of your school's roster data. When you share data with Mega Seating Plan, it will be transferred via ClassLink and stored on our servers, located within European data boundaries. All personally identifiable data is encrypted. This agreement outlines how Mega Seating Plan protects your data.

##### Transfer and Use of Personal Information

When registering for Mega Seating Plan's SIS link (provided by ClassLink), you will provide consent for us to transfer data within the agreed scopes. This consent is perpetual until either party withdraws it. When you revoke consent, we will cease transferring data from your SIS and delete all of your data that has been stored on our servers. This data deletion will include all student and class data imported from your SIS, but individual teacher user accounts may remain in place to allow their continued use of the Mega Seating Plan platform (with no SIS link). Deletion of data shall take place as soon as is practicable and no later than 72 hours from the withdrawal of consent. Withdrawal of consent does not necessarily terminate any commercial relationship between you and us, and you may continue to take advantage of other benefits of Mega Seating Plan that do not require an SIS link.

Data transferred from your SIS and stored by Mega Seating Plan includes the following:

* Details of teachers at your school, including their name and email address. This is for the purpose of establishing a user account on Mega Seating Plan.
* Details of class groups at your school, including lists of students and associated staff.
* Details of timetables at your school. This is for the purpose of providing planning tools for teachers.
* Details of students at your school, including names, email address and demographics. This is to allow seating plans to be generated and annotated using this data. All personally-identifiable data is stored encrypted.

Data is stored in a database located in the European Union. Access to student data (and the ability to decrypt it) is limited to the teacher of that class and other users that the teacher has explicitly agreed to share it with. Within Platinum schools, all seating plans are shared with all other users in that school (for the purpose of substitute lessons and monitoring).

##### Support

Support is available via an online support helpdesk. To provide this support, it may be necessary for us to sign in to Mega Seating Plan as one of your teachers, thus allowing us to see student data connected to that teacher.

##### Data Lifecycle

We will attempt to synchronise demographic/class data with your SIS (via ClassLink) at least every 24 hours. Due to the nature of ClassLink's caching, some changes may take longer to propagate.

When classes are deactivated or deleted from your SIS, they will be archived on Mega Seating Plan for three months; this ensures that teachers can still access seating plans for this class for a period (useful for mid-year class changes). After the three month period, these classes, their students and all related seating plans will be permanently deleted from Mega Seating Plan's servers.

##### Other documents

For further information, please refer to our [privacy policy](https://www.seatingplan.com/privacy), [data protection statement (including GDPR compliance)](https://www.seatingplan.com/gdpr) and [terms of use](https://www.seatingplan.com/terms).

Download the Mega Seating Plan app to your phone to learn student names fast

[Facebook](https://www.facebook.com/megaseatingplan) [Instagram](https://www.instagram.com/megaseatingplan) [BlueSky](https://bsky.app/profile/seatingplan.bsky.social) [X/Twitter](https://www.twitter.com/megaseatingplan) [LinkedIn](https://www.linkedin.com/in/robcowen-teacher/) [\[email protected\]](https://www.seatingplan.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)

Mega Seating Plan Ltd is registered as a company in England and Wales (registration number 10358390).

Mega Seating Plan Ltd is registered with the Information Commissioner's Office (#ZA331933).

Mega Seating Plan Ltd is registered for VAT in the United Kingdom (GB394723269) and in the European Union (EU372042551).

© Mega Seating Plan Ltd 2015-2024

© Mega Seating Plan Ltd 2015-2024
